Eric Guillermo Estrada Oajaca

310-686-8047 | e.estradaoajaca@gmail.com | Gardena, CA

Objective

Obtain an internship working with professionally experienced Civil Engineers where my strong analytical and problem-solving skills will be utilized for interests in Transportation, Wastewater Treatment, or Hydraulic Design. I want to enhance my work-ethic and expand my potential.

Education

University of California, Los Angeles Pursuing B.S. Degree in Civil Engineering Expected Graduation Date: Spring 2021

Cumulative GPA: 3.825

Relevant Course Experience: Introduction to Transportation Engineering, Hydraulic and Hydrologic Design, Introduction to Water Resources Engineering, Hydraulic Analysis, Environmental Engineering Unit Operations and Processes Laboratory, Elementary Structural Analysis, Introduction to Hydrology, Introduction to Environmental Engineering Science, Introduction to Mechanics of Deformable Solids, Statics, Science of Engineering Materials, Elementary Fluid Mechanics

Experience

City of Los Angeles, Bureau of Engineering, Wastewater Conveyance Construction Division

Summer 2019

- Gather documents and data using Navigate LA to assist and design for the S.E.W.E.R.S. (Super Expedited Wastewater Emergency Rehabilitation for Sewers) Program
- Watched CCTV videos to assess and report the hazards that needed to be addressed for Pipes running throughout the City of Los Angeles
- Utilized Navigate LA to determine which utility lines surrounded existing Pipes to prevent hazard when excavating/implementing the Rehabilitation
- Prepared a Power-Point Presentation on the implementation of Rib(Ring Beam) and Lagging (and its use as a primary tunnel liner to shore horizontal excavations in soft ground) on a Relief Sewer since the method was unfamiliar to fellow colleagues
- Process Time and Material paperwork and supplemental Invoices; furthermore, consistently communicated with Project Inspector
- Accompanied Supervisor to construction sites to determine a project's phase and communicate with Contractors to assure that all city requirements were implemented

Research

Undergraduate Assistant, Environmental Engineering Lab Under Jennifer Jay

Fall 2017

2017-Now

W18,S20

03/2017

06/2017 05/2017 03/2016

- Observed the concentration level of lead in soil at 100 different local parks near Los Angeles to further observe whether it was a potential threat to humans living in the local communities.
- Utilized leadership and cooperation skills to work with fellow students on gathering materials and necessary analytical data to present to Engineering professors

Special Skills

Personal: Fluent in Spanish, Service-Oriented, Takes Preemptive Action, Adaptive Team Player, Remarkable Communication Skills, Strong Organization Skills, Optimistic and Energetic Attitude. Computer: MATLAB, Microsoft Office, Google Earth, Intermediate-AutoCAD, R-Studio, & **ARCGIS**

Professional Organizations

Activities

UCLA Center for Excellence and Engineering Diversity (CEED)	
Chi Epsilon (XE)- American Civil Engineering Honor Society- Bo	oard Me
ASCE (UCLA): American Society of Civil Engineers: Environment	<mark>ental De</mark>
The state of the s	-

ember, Marshal 2019-Now esign, Project Director 2019-Now Engineers Without Borders (EWB) - Nicaragua Project, Design Team 2018-Now Mentor SEAS Program 2017-Now S.O.L.E.S. (UCLA): Society of Latino Engineers and Scientists- CEED-Tri-Org Outreach

2017-2019 N.S.B.E.(UCLA): National Society of Black Engineers 2017-2018 A.S.C.E. Concrete Canoe 2017-2018

Honors and Awards

UCLA Achievement Scholarship
Summa Cum Laude, Golden State Seal Award, and Seal of Biliteracy
Chevron Scholar, M.E.T.A. Foundation Scholar, Vivian Clark Scholarship
Frederick Douglass and Susan B. Anthony Award

HSSEAS Dean's List (GPA 3.7+)